# **Patrick Naish**

Holiday: 14 Porchester Road, Newbury, Berkshire RG14 7QJ

01635 44487

Term: 10 Westridge Road, Southampton, Hampshire SO17 2HQ

07786 399343

patrick@pmnaish.co.uk

## Personal statement

Currently in my third year at Southampton University, I am a Software Engineering MEng (<a href="http://www.ecs.soton.ac.uk/programmes/g600-meng-software-engineering-4-yrs">http://www.ecs.soton.ac.uk/programmes/g600-meng-software-engineering-4-yrs</a>) student with an interest in software design and security. I have a large amount of experience working in development groups, both within university work and in my own projects.

## Qualifications

Course/qualification MEng Software Engineering	Dates from and to 2010-present	Education institution University of Southampton	<b>Grade</b> TBC
A2 Mathematics	2009-2010		A*
A2 Further	2009-2010		С
Mathematics		St. Bartholomew's School,	
A2 Computing	2009-2010	Newbury	Α
A2 Physics	2009-2010	•	В
GCŚEs	2006-2008		A*-B

So far on my course, I have taken modules in:

- Programming Principles
- Advanced Programming
- Discrete Mathematics for Computer Science
- Introduction to Formal Methods
- Digital Electronics
- Data Structures and Algorithms
- Software Engineering
- System Administration Tools and Techniques
- Computational Systems
- Human-Computer Interaction
- Software Analysis and Design
- Operating Systems
- Theory of Computing
- Professional and Legal Issues
- Principles of Computer Graphics
- Scripting Languages
- Hypertext and Web Technologies
- Management 1
- Database Systems
- Distributed Computing
- Communications and Networks
- Compiler Engineering
- Software Engineering Group Project
- Artificial Intelligence
- Computer Architecture
- Personal and Professional Development
- Engineering Maths for Computer Science

In the first year of my Software Engineering course I averaged a 1<sup>st</sup> overall. In my second year I averaged fractionally under a 1<sup>st</sup>. My third year, including a large individual development project, is progressing well so far.

## Skills acquired

- A diagnosis of Asperger's Syndrome when I was 13 years old lead to me self-teaching my GCSEs, during which time I developed strong self-discipline and utilised my desire to learn to obtain my grades from A\*-A, and one B.
- Working at the Newbury Library for several years has helped me to develop good interpersonal skills, and experience of handling sensitive data securely.
- My summer work at IBM Hursley gave me an insight into the workings of a software company, and an awareness of the teamworking skills and processes that are required in such an environment.
- My summer internship at Micro Focus gave me experience in working in a SCRUM team, with development in an OSGi framework.

# Key skills and achievements

- My first programming language was C, which I started about 9 years ago.
- I am a reasonably strong Java developer, having several modules over the first and second years of
  my course that teach Java coding and best practices. I have also gained some experience in
  working with Jetty webservers and the OSGi framework.
- I can program in r5rs Scheme, thanks to my Computational Systems module.
- I did 2 weeks of summer work at the IBM Hursley Lab, during which time I helped to debug an internal Extreme Blue project (LogWeaver).
- I participated in the DevXS event (devxs.org), in which we were challenged to create a web application that provided a service to students. This was done in a group, over 29 hours, using Python. In our group, we created intr (intr.ep.io), which is a framework for society managements at university. This is currently being developed into a full system known as Treehouse (website pending).
- I am currently in a group of developers who are creating Owings (owin.gs), a system for managing group expenses. This is helping me to gain experience in Ruby and Rails, as well as general web development.
- I learned a significant amount of Javascript, including the dojo framework, during my internship at Micro Focus.

## **Employment history**

Job title	Dates	Company/Team name
Volunteer	Summer 2008	West Berkshire Mencap
Summer Library Volunteer	Summers 2009, 2010, 2011	West Berkshire Libraries
Sunday Library Assistant	25/04/2010 - 27/06/2010	West Berkshire Libraries
Owings Developer	January 2012 – ongoing	Team Owin.gs
Summer Intern	June 2012 -September 2012	Micro Focus UK, Team Orion
Christmas Intern	December 2012	Micro Focus UK

#### Interests

Computer and system security, web applications, software development process.

#### Referees

Available on request.